Do you sometimes find yourself drawing random patterns and designs during meetings and lectures?
你是否有时会在开会或听讲座时，不自觉地画些随意的图案和纹样？
Some people believe it shows you aren’t listening or paying attention.
有些人认为这是心不在焉、没有认真听讲的表现。
However, there are studies which claim the opposite, and that doodling might actually be beneficial.
但有研究却得出了相反的结论，认为涂鸦实际上可能是有益的。
Doodling seems to be ubiquitous.
涂鸦这种行为似乎无处不在。
In the past it was seen as a mindless activity and a product of the absentminded.
在过去，它被视为一种无意识的举动，是心不在焉的产物。
However, in 2016, an article on the Harvard University website discussed the idea that random drawings may assist memory retention and concentration.
但2016年哈佛大学官网上的一篇文章指出，随手涂鸦有助于增强记忆力和专注力。
The article highlights that 26 of 44 American presidents were known to doodle, with Ronald Reagan famous for drawing cowboys.
这篇文章还提到，美国44任总统中有26位都有涂鸦的习惯，其中罗纳德·里根就因画牛仔而闻名。
A 2009 study conducted by psychologist Jackie Andrade asked 40 people to listen to a ‘dull and rambling’ voice message.
2009年，心理学家杰姬·安德拉德开展了一项研究，她让40人聆听一段“枯燥冗长”的语音信息。
Half of the group were asked to doodle and shade in a picture. Those who did were able to recall 29% more of the information contained in the message.
研究人员要求其中一半人边听边涂鸦并给图案上色，结果发现这部分人能多回忆起29%的信息。
Some experts believe that embracing your creative and artistic sides during meetings may engage your mind.
一些专家认为，在开会时发挥自己的创意和艺术天赋，能让大脑保持活跃状态。
Jesse Prinz, a renowned professor of philosophy, actively encourages his students to doodle. He believes that doodling is the ‘attentional sweet spot’.
著名哲学教授杰西·普林茨就积极鼓励学生涂鸦，他认为涂鸦是“注意力的最佳状态”。
And it might not just be good for your concentration.
而且涂鸦的好处可能不止提升专注力这一点。
An artist known as Mr Doodle has made a career out of his scribbles.
一位名叫“涂鸦先生”的艺术家就靠自己的随手涂鸦开创了一番事业。
He sells his art online and also goes to people’s homes to decorate their walls.
他不仅在网上售卖自己的作品，还会上门帮人装饰墙面。
It seems that random drawing to aid concentration might be becoming more of a thing.
如今，用随手涂鸦来提升专注力的做法似乎越来越流行。
People like Sunni Brown, an advocate for doodling, teach adults how to sketch and scribble in the workplace.
桑妮·布朗等涂鸦倡导者还会教成年人如何在工作场合随手画些草图和涂鸦。
So, the next time you see someone haphazardly drawing pictures during a meeting, it might be a sign that they are listening more than you think.
所以下次再看到有人在开会时随意画画，这或许恰恰说明他们比你想象中听得更认真。